http://www.bakingmad.com/privacy-policy

Privacy Policy | Baking Mad
You'll need JavaScript enabled to experience the full functionality of this site. Please enable JavaScript by following the instructions at enable-javascript.com.
Recipes
Bread & Dough RecipesCake RecipesConfectionery RecipesCookies & Biscuit RecipesCupcakes & Muffin RecipesDessert RecipesHomemade Ice Cream & Ice Lolly RecipesIcing & Buttercream RecipesJams, Marmalade, Chutneys & Preserves MakingPancakes & Crepe Batters RecipesPastries, Pies & Tart RecipesScones & Shortcake RecipesSweet Sauces RecipesTraybake Recipes
Explore All Recipes
Baking Tips
In The Mix
Footer Pages
Privacy Policy
Back to Footer Pages
Privacy Policy
Who are we?
This website www.bakingmad.com (the “Website”) is owned and operated by The Silver Spoon Company, a division of British Sugar Plc. (registered in England and Wales under company number 00315158) (called in this notice “we”, “our” or “us”).
Purpose of this notice
This privacy notice tells you about the information we collect about you when you visit our Website or otherwise provide us with information.
It also tells you how you can exercise Your Rights, including the right to object to some of the data handling we carry out.
What personal data do we collect?
Site traffic data and information about your computer
How do we use this data?
When you browse our Website, we use cookies to collect:
Information about your use of our Website – we collect standard internet log information and details of visitor behaviour patterns.
We use this information to record visitor numbers, their use of different areas of the Website and any useful features or links. We do not use this information in any way that would identify you personally.
We use third parties, Google Analytics and Hot Jar to collect this information but it is only processed in a way which does not identify anyone. We do not make, and do not allow Google or Hot Jar to make, any attempt to find out the identities of those visiting our website;
Information about your computer; this includes your IP address, operating system and browser type.
We use this information to help maintain the security of our Website and to identify trends so that we can improve its performance.
We also use this information to customise the Website according to your interests and to ensure the Website’s content is presented as effectively as possible for you and to enable you to participate in interactive features of the Website, when you choose to do so.
We do not use this information in any way that would identify you personally.
We collect this information for the purpose of our legitimate interests in maintaining and managing our Website and ensuring its security. For more information about how we use cookies on our Website, see our Cookies Policy To opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics across all websites, visit http://tools.google.com/dipage/gaoptout
How long do we keep this information for?
We will only keep information about your visit to our Website for as long as is necessary for the purposes we’ve mentioned. Typically we delete user browsing information every 24 months.
Who do we share this information with?
We share information about visitors to our Website with service providers who help us administer and manage the Website.
We also share information about your use of our Website with advertising networks, although you cannot be personally identified from this information.
Where do we transfer this information to?
Information we collect about your use of our Website is held by our service provider(s) on secure servers located outside the European Economic Area (EEA).
We protect your privacy by ensuring our service provider(s) are registered with the EU-US Privacy Shield. If you require further information about these safeguards, please contact us.
Information you send us
How do we use this data?
You do not have to supply us directly with any information when you use our Website. If you choose to use our ‘contact us’ feature or otherwise get in touch with us, we will use the information you send us for the purpose of responding to your enquiry. When we use your personal data for this purpose, we do so for our legitimate business interest in communicating with you in accordance with your wishes and expectations. We will also use this data for the purpose of our legitimate interests in accessing appropriate professional advice and in order to ensure we comply with legal obligations to which our business is subject.
General enquiries about our recruitment procedures are welcome but we are not able to consider CVs or job applications sent to us via this Website. If you do use this Website to send us this type of information, it will be securely deleted on receipt.
How long do we keep this information for?
We will only keep your information for as long as is necessary in order to manage your query. We usually keep records of routine queries for 12 months but in some cases (for example where the query relates to a contract between us, or where we need to obtain legal advice in order to respond to a complaint) we may need to retain a record of our communications for up to 6 years.
Who do we share this information with?
We will share your data with our service providers and our professional advisers if this is necessary in order to resolve a query or complaint.
Otherwise we will not share your information with any third party unless:
we have your permission;
we are required to do so by law;
this is necessary so that we can enforce our terms of use, rights or property or the rights or property of any third party; or
this is necessary in connection with the sale of our business or its assets (in which case your details will be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchaser’s advisers and will be passed to the new owners).
Where do we transfer this information to?
Information you send us via our Website is held by our service provider(s) on secure servers located outside the European Economic Area (EEA). We protect your privacy by ensuring our service provider(s) are registered with the EU-US Privacy Shield. If you require further information about these safeguards, please contact us.
Information about your on-line transactions
How do we use this data?
If you use our Website to place an order with us, we will ask you to supply us with the information we need in order to process your order. We collect this information because it is necessary for the performance of our contract with you.
How long do we keep this information for?
We keep information regarding your on-line transactions for 6 years.
Who do we share this information with?
We share information about your on-line transactions with our suppliers and service providers where this is necessary to manage on-line payments, or to fulfil and deliver on-line orders.
Otherwise we will not share your information with any third party unless:
we have your permission;
we are required to do so by law;
this is necessary so that we can enforce our terms of use, rights or property or the rights or property of any third party; or
this is necessary in connection with the sale of our business or its assets (in which case your details will be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchaser’s advisers and will be passed to the new owners).
Where do we transfer this information to?
Information we hold about your on-line transactions is held by our service provider(s) on secure servers located outside the European Economic Area (EEA). We protect your privacy by ensuring our service provider(s) are registered with the EU-US Privacy Shield. If you require further information about these safeguards, please contact us.
Information you give us when you sign up for our newsletter, enter a competition, prize draw, or promotion, complete a survey, or set up an online account or profile
How do we use this data?
You do not have to supply us directly with your personal data when you use our Website. However, some communications, services and facilities can only be provided if you supply us with relevant details. For example, if you sign up for our newsletter, enter a competition, prize draw or promotion, complete a survey, or register as a site user you will be asked to provide us with your contact details. If we ask you to supply us with information that is not strictly necessary in order for us to provide you with the communication, service or facility you are interested in, we will make this clear. This might be because it’s useful to us in helping us learn more about our customers or enhance our products and services.
If you do sign up for our newsletter, enter a competition, prize draw or promotion, complete a survey, or set up an online account or profile we will use the personal data you provide :
to provide you with newsletters and other promotional information that you request from us;
to provide you with specific information about our products and services where you request this;
to manage your online account;
to improve our understanding of the needs and interests of our customers and contacts; and
to notify you about changes to our services.
When we use your personal data for these purposes, we do so for our legitimate interests in managing and administering online accounts and for our legitimate business interests in developing and promoting our goods and services and communicating with you in accordance with your wishes and expectations. You can object to our use of your data for these purposes at any time. For further information about the way we use your data for direct marketing purposes see our direct marketing section.
We will also use this data for the purpose of our legitimate interests in accessing appropriate professional advice and in order to ensure we comply with legal obligations to which our business is subject.
If you provide us with your information in connection with a competition entry, prize draw or promotion, we will use this to administer our competition, to communicate competition results where relevant and to deliver prizes. When we use your personal data for these purposes, we do so because it is necessary for us to collect and use this information for the performance of our contract with you in accordance with our competition rules.
How long do we keep this information for?
Information we hold for the purpose of managing your online account or profile is held by us for as long as your account or profile continues to be active.
Information we hold for market research purposes is not usually held in a form that will identify you for longer than 12 months.
Information we hold in connection with the management of competitions, prize draws, and promotions is usually held for 12 months.
Information we hold for direct marketing purposes so that we can send you newsletters and other promotional material is held by us for as long as you continue to be interested in receiving our marketing communications. However you can tell us to stop using your details for marketing purposes at any time by contacting us.
Who do we share this information with?
We share this data where necessary with our suppliers, service providers and professional advisers.
Otherwise we will not share your information with any third party unless:
we have your permission;
we are required to do so by law;
this is necessary so that we can enforce our terms of use, rights or property or the rights or property of any third party; or
this is necessary in connection with the sale of our business or its assets (in which case your details will be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchaser’s advisers and will be passed to the new owners).
Where do we transfer this information to?
Information we collect when you sign up for our newsletter, enter a competition, prize draw or promotion, complete a survey or set up an online account or profile is held by our service provider(s) on secure servers located outside the European Economic Area (EEA). We protect your privacy by ensuring our service provider(s) are registered with the EU-US Privacy Shield. If you require further information about these safeguards, please contact us.
Direct Marketing
How do we use this data?
We will use contact details you give us to deliver promotional information that you request or that we feel may interest you. We will also use this information to gain insights into the needs and interests of our customer base and to evaluate the effectiveness of our marketing activities.
Unless we have obtained your contact details in the course of an online sale or negotiation for a sale and you have indicated you are happy to receive our marketing communications, we will only contact you for marketing purposes by email if you have consented to this.
When we use your data for our direct marketing purposes we do so for our legitimate interests in promoting our business and the goods and services we offer.
How long do we keep this information for?
We keep information for direct marketing purposes for as long as you continue to be interested in receiving our marketing communications. We use tracking technology to help us monitor the effectiveness of our e-marketing and delete contacts from our e-marketing database after 2 years of recipient inactivity.
You can tell us to stop using your details for marketing purposes by contacting us and can opt out of email marketing at any time by using our unsubscribe feature.
Who do we share this information with?
Where necessary we share this data with our suppliers and service providers.
Otherwise we will not share your information with any third party unless:
we have your permission;
we are required to do so by law;
this is necessary so that we can enforce our terms of use, rights or property or the rights or property of any third party; or
this is necessary in connection with the sale of our business or its assets (in which case your details will be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchaser’s advisers and will be passed to the new owners).
Where do we transfer this information to?
Information we hold for direct marketing purposes is held by our service provider(s) on secure servers located outside the European Economic Area (EEA). We protect your privacy by ensuring our service provider(s) are registered with the EU-US Privacy Shield. If you require further information about these safeguards, please contact us.
Your Rights
You can ask us at any time to provide you with a copy of your personal data. In relation to personal data you have supplied to us, and which is held by us for the purpose of entering into a contract between us or on the basis of your consent, you are entitled to ask us for a copy of this information in a structured, commonly used and machine readable format so that you can reuse it or share it with other organisations.
If you think the personal data we hold about you is inaccurate or incomplete, you can ask us to correct it or complete it.
In some circumstances you also have the right to object to our processing of your data and can ask us to restrict our use of your data and to delete it.
There are some exceptions to these rights, however. For example, it will not be possible for us to delete your data if we are required by law to keep it or if we hold it in connection with a contract with you. Similarly, access to your data may be refused if making the information available would reveal personal information about another person or if we are legally prevented from disclosing such information.
If you wish to exercise any of these rights you should contact us.
Contacting us and your rights of Complaint
Questions, comments or requests concerning this privacy notice are welcomed and should be addressed to Data Protection Coordinator at The Silver Spoon Company, Western House, Lynchwood Business Park, Peterborough, PE2 6BP.
If you have a concern about the way we handle your personal data you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioner (ICO). You can find details of how to do this on the ICO website at https://ico.org.uk/concerns/ or by calling their helpline on 0303 123 1113.
This privacy notice was last updated March 2020
Recipes
Bread & Dough RecipesCake RecipesConfectionery RecipesCookies & Biscuit RecipesCupcakes & Muffin RecipesDessert RecipesHomemade Ice Cream & Ice Lolly RecipesIcing & Buttercream RecipesJams, Marmalade, Chutneys & Preserves MakingPancakes & Crepe Batters RecipesPastries, Pies & Tart RecipesScones & Shortcake RecipesSweet Sauces RecipesTraybake Recipes
More
Baking Tips
In The Mix
About Baking Mad
Follow Us
© British Sugar plc 2020
Contact UsTerms & ConditionsPrivacy PolicyCookie PolicyModern Slavery ActSitemapCompetition Terms & Conditions
Create Account
Sign In
We are currently reviewing the account section of Baking Mad which means you will no longer be able to sign in or create a new account on the website for the foreseeable future. You can still browse the site and view our delicious recipes (you can even print them or email them to yourself so you have them to hand). We apologise for any inconvenience this may cause.
We are currently reviewing the account section of Baking Mad which means you will no longer be able to sign in or create a new account on the website for the foreseeable future. You can still browse the site and view our delicious recipes (you can even print them or email them to yourself so you have them to hand). We apologise for any inconvenience this may cause.
We use cookies to provide you with the best browsing experience. By continuing to use this site you are agreeing to our use of cookies. To find out more, please read our cookie policy.
At Baking Mad we love cookies. We even place them on your computer. These ones don't contain chocolate chips, but they do allow us to provide you with the best experience. By continuing to use this site you are agreeing to our use of cookies. To find out more, please read our cookie policy. To bake some of your own, visit our cookie recipes page!
Close
